本字幕由 PTT同志影视作品板 2013重新校稿
原字幕取自网路资源  仅供学习 禁用任何商业盈利行为
校稿：Coldsis、hahanjia、mohiwa
同志亦凡人 Queer As Folk S01E22 (第一季完)
谁联系上布莱恩了吗?
Has anybody heard from Brian?
我都找了他一整天了
I've been trying to reach him all day.
我也是,  但是他一直不回电话
Me too, but he hasn't returned any of my calls.
希望没出什麽事
I hope he's all right.
我想知道这个阳寿将尽的男人在做些什麽
I wonder how the condemned man's spending his final hours?
-忏悔 　　　　　  -嗑药
-Doing penance? 　-Doing drugs.
尽可能多上一些男人？
Doing as many guys as he can?
猜对了！
Bingo.
也许我们不该帮他庆生
Maybe we shouldn't go through with this.
他明确表示不想别人提起这件事
He made it clear he doesn't want to be reminded.
我们应该提都不要提
We're not even supposed to mention it.
事情可能会变得很糟  很糟
It could get ugly. Really ugly.
无论如何  这事是有历史意义的
Still, it is an event of historic proportion.
像是登陆月球  或者共产主义的沦陷一样
Like the moon landing, or the fall of communism.
我们作为朋友应该纪念一下
It is our duty as friends to commemorate it.
确保他会记住这一天
And make sure he remembers it.
永远记住
Always.
布莱恩
Brian!
早安喔
Hello in there.
起床了  贪睡鬼
Wake up, sleepy head.
你们在这里干什麽
What're you doing here?
你还没听说？
Oh, you mean you haven't heard?
这是你人生最後一天了
It's the last day of the rest of your life.
我死了吗
Did I die?
没有  但你会巴不得你死了
No, but you'll wish you had.
你三十岁了
You're 30.
-走开  -抱歉  爷爷
- Go away! - Sorry, grampa.
我说走开
I said go away.
你可没这麽走运
No such luck.
抓住他
Grab him!
小心点  他会咬人的
Careful, he bites.
拿着他的Gucci (名牌)
Get his gucci,
普拉达  亚曼尼 (名牌)
Prada, Armani.
天啊  真是个名牌女王
Jesus, what a label queen.
起来啦
Upsy-daisy.
别烦我
Leave me alone.
相信我吧  布莱恩 这绝对会让你
Believe me, Brian, this is going to hurt you
比我们还不舒服
a lot more than it's going to hurt us.
抓住他
Get him!
这是什麽
What is this?
恭喜你正式加入
Your official membership
行将就木同志协会
to the dead faggots society.
你是谁  协会的创办人？
And who are you, the fucking founding father?
你知道  真的要
Oh, you know, you really are going
换些新词了
to need to get some new material.
既然你现在是「我们」的一员了
Now that you are... one of "us".
等等  他不该先许个愿吗
Wait, shouldn't he make a wish first?
宝贝  他已经许过了
Oh, hon, he already has.
但他还是三十岁
He's still 30.
谁想来块忌日蛋糕
Hey, who wants some deathday cake?
-忌日蛋糕         -我要
-Deathday cake? 　-Oh, yeah.
忌日蛋糕?
Deathday cake?
我来一点
I'll have some...
既然我没有什麽年龄问题要解决
Since I won't have to deal with the whole age issue
很长时间之内都不会有
for a long, long time.
没这麽糟糕
It's not so bad.
忽视你的年龄  向前走
You forget about it, you go on.
特别当你想到你的新生活
Especially when you consider the alternative.
想想有什麽样乐趣在等着你
Think of all the fun you're going to have,
搬到纽约去  和那些帅哥们狂欢
going to New York, partying with the big boys.
你的人生才刚开始
You've just only begun to fuck.
我不去纽约了
I'm not going to New York.
什麽
What?
我说我不．．．
I said I'm not...
我不去纽约了
I'm not going to New York.
那份工作泡汤了
The job fell through.
你他妈怎麽不告诉我
Why the fuck didn't you tell me?
告诉你了又能怎样
What difference does it make?
你和大卫有自己的安排
You've got your plans with David.
我知道  但是
I know, but...
没什麽大不了的
It's no big deal.
怎麽会
No big deal?
你一直期待着呢
It's all you've been talking about,
离开这里  不再回头
leaving, not looking back.
你都开始要卖你的阁楼了
You even put your loft on the market.
我可以停止出售
Well, I can just take it off the market.
反正无所谓了
Anyway, It doesn't matter.
我已经死了
I'm already dead.
好  标着「P」的箱子  运到哪里？
Okay, stuff marked "p", where does that go?
所有标着「P」的箱子运去波特兰
All boxes marked with "p" go to Portland.
-「S」？  -仓库
-"S"? 　　-Storage.
嗨  迈克
Hey, Michael!
你没说搬家公司的人今天就来
You didn't you tell me the moving men were coming today.
我以为我说过了
Oh, I thought I did.
这个是要放仓库的
That one's storage. okay?
我得赶快打包我的东西
I better finish packing my stuff.
不用了
No, it's okay.
我已经打包完了
I did it.
可我不知道
But I don't know...
我不知道哪些要放仓库   哪些要带去波特兰
I don't know what's an "s" and what's a "p".
星际队长  机器人  漫画都标着「P」
Captain Astro, robots, comic books are a "p",
衣服  视频设备  还有
Clothes, video equipment... oh, and...
你该把这个给你的朋友们还有你妈妈
You should give this to your friends and your mother.
是我们的新地址
That's our new address.
新地址  我们什麽时候
New address? When did we...
什麽时候找到房子住了
when did we get a place?
我在网上租了套房
I rented a house on the Internet.
你怎麽没跟我说
Why didn't you tell me?
来不及说啊  我是说　那房子可抢手了
Well, there just wasn't time. I mean, we would've lost it.
你会喜欢那个地方的
You're going to love the place,
有中庭  有泳池
It's got an atrium, a pool.
听上去不错, 嗯...
Sounds great. Um...
我看我得去取机票了
Look, I'm going to go pick up the tickets.
不必了
No, don't have to.
我去过了
I did it.
这样啊
Oh. Oh, well...
好吧  那我就去打电话给泰德
Okay. Then i'm going to call Ted.
他要载我们去机场
He was going to give us a ride to the airport.
不用了  我叫了车
No need. I booked a car.
有什麽事我能做的吗
Is there anything I can do?
嗯, 对了, 你可以...
Uh, yeah, you can...
站在那里 看起来美美的
Stand there and look gorgeous,
你最擅长这个了
Which you do so beautifully.
爱上能打点好一切的男人不是很好？
Isn't it great to be in love with a guy who does everything?
是啊
Yeah. Um...
我想我可以去美容沙龙
So I guess I'll just go to the beauty parlour
做做美甲
and get my nails done.
要是保证人从美国公民自由协会来电话
When binder calls from the ACLU,
把他接进来
put him right through.
今天真是充满惊喜啊
Well, this day is just full of surprises.
你们是来玩  还是来找律师的
Is this a fun visit or do you two need a good lawyer?
呵, 我们是来吃午饭的
Hm, what we need is a good lunch.
我们觉得我们...应该带布雷克出去
We thought we'd... take Blake out,
如果你允许的话
If you can spare him.
我倒是愿意  可惜他不在
Oh, I'd be happy to, if he was here.
他今天没来
He hasn't come in today.
噢...对
Oh... that's right.
我, 我想起来了
I-I forgot that he...
他今天早上说他不太舒服
He mentioned this morning he wasn't feeling well.
他, 呃..., 对, 我...我想他是得流感了...
He, uh... yeah, I... I think he's got the flu...
或是别的病, 呃...
or something and, uh...
他,  他不想传染给别人
H-he didn't want to share his germs with anyone.
真是想得很周到  但说实话  泰德
Well, that's thoughtful but frankly, Teddy,
这不是他第一次跷班了
This isn't the first time.
他即使来上班  也没有什麽效率
And when he is here, he's slow
他完成不了自己的工作
and he doesn't complete tasks we assign him.
其他的合夥人都很生气  他们想开除他
The other partners are pissed. They want him gone.
茉蕾妮,  分机.
Melanie, line one.
我会和他谈的. 我, 我不知道这件事...
I'll talk to him. I-I don't know...
是我的电话
Oh, that's my call.
失陪了,  伙计们
Excuse me, guys.
你好  我是茉蕾妮·马库斯
Yes, hi. This is Melanie Marcus.
我正在..
Uh, I'm getting...
什麽都别说
Don't say anything.
我?  我才不会说呢
Me? Oh, I wouldn't dream of it.
除非他不想和人分享的不是感冒
Except It's not his germs he didn't want to share.
是他的毒品
It's his drugs.
真感激你什麽都没说
Thank you for not saying anything.
你为什麽总是这麽愤世嫉俗呢
Why do you always have to be so fucking cynical?
我没有  不过你知道吗
I'm not cynical. But you know what?
我宁愿愤世嫉俗  也不想逃避现实
I'd rather be fucking cynical than in fucking denial.
他感冒了 喉咙痛
Well, he has a cold and a sore throat
因为发烧全身酸痛
accompanied by the aches and pains of fever
还有鼻塞
and congestion.
如果症状持续  我们就得看医生了
If the symptoms persist, we'll consult a physician.
现在,  我们去虾船吃饭吧
Now, let's go to the shrimpboat.
你会喜欢这次的烧烤的,  小詹
You'll love the barbecue, Jen.
这是一项同志亲友团的传统
It's a PFLAG tradition.
黛比发起的
Debbie started it.
还有这麽多棘手的问题要解决
There're so many serious issues to deal with,
我只是想和你的孩子一起开心一天
I just thought it was a nice way to have fun with your kids.
我都等不及了
I'm looking forward to it.
我不知道贾斯汀想不想去
I'm not that sure how eager Justin's going to be.
我会劝他的
I'll work on him.
他们把所有东西都印到邮票上了
They've got everything on stamps these days.
音乐家,  鸟类,
Composers, birds,
甚至还有三个臭皮匠
Even the three stooges.
他们什麽时候才会印上「超级名gay」
So when are they going to have "famous fags"?
亲爱的  你能被印到69分的邮票上去 (69意指性姿势)
You can be on the 69-cent stamp, honey.
嗨,  妈妈
Hey, mom.
你要和你妈去参加同志亲友团的烧烤聚餐
You're going with your mom to the PFLAG barbecue
我不想听到你说一个「不」
And I don't want to hear another word about it.
好
Okay.
这些年来迈克不也乖乖听我的话去了吗
How do you think I got Michael to go all those years?
这次他却去不了, 自从他成年以来可是头一回
It's the first one he's gonna have missed since he was 18.
至少他找到了归属
Well, at least he's where he belongs,
和他爱的男人在一起
with the man he loves.
但却身处地球另一端
On the opposite side of the goddamn world.
这样想吧,  黛比
Look at it this way, Deb;
你都拥有他这麽久了
You've had him all this time.
听听
Listen to him.
跟你说吧　我们可以一起盯着贾斯汀
Tell you what, we can share Justin.
很快他也会离开
Pretty soon he'll be gone too.
他就要毕业啦
Graduation's coming up...
参加毕业舞会...
The prom...
毕业舞会
The prom.
当年我的伴儿是康妮·康斯特洛
I went with Connie Costello.
200磅的胖子裹在紫色绸缎里
200 pounds wrapped in purple satin.
看起来简直像只人形大葡萄
She was like a stuffed grape leaf.
当然,  我无法和意中人共赴舞会
Of course, I couldn't take who I really wanted to.
兰斯·罗科
Lance Rocco.
舌吻高手
Pisser of a kisser.
我和康妮跳舞跳得欢
I wound up dancing with Connie.
他却压根没来
He wound up not going at all.
反正我也不准备去
Yeah, I'm not going either.
为什麽不去?
Why not?
维克也说了啊,  那是给异性恋去的.
Like vic said, it's for straight kids.
人人都能去毕业舞会啊,  不管你是异男或同志
I think the prom's for everyone, straight or gay.
正解
That's right.
那可是...成年的必经之路
It's one of those... those growing up experiences.
你知道, 那个词儿到底怎麽说来着?
You know, what in the hell do they call it?
成人礼?
Rites of passage?
没错
That's it.
就好比...给出你的第一次
It's like... like losing your virginity
或是...或是...取得驾照
or... or... or getting your driver's license.
我不想看到你因为觉得自己是异类
I'd just hate to see you deprive yourself of the experience
而失去宝贵的人生经历
because you think you don't belong.
嗨,  小泰
Hey, Teddy.
你去哪儿了?
Where've you been?
出去了
Out.
你感觉怎样?
How're you feeling?
棒极了
Great.
那你怎麽没去上班
Then why weren't you at work?
我今天过去想接你一起吃饭
I stopped by to take you out to lunch,
茉蕾妮说你请了病假没去
Melanie said you'd called in sick.
是啊,  我, 呃...
Yeah. I had, uh...
是有点小不舒服
one of those 24-hour bug things. but...
但现在感觉好多了
I'm feeling a lot better now.
你最好别再请假了
Well, you'd better not miss any more days because...
不然他们可能
They might...
别担心
Don't worry.
明天早上一起来
I'll be there all bright-eyed and bushy-tailed...
我就焕然一新  精神奋发地去上班
First thing in the morning.
我保证
Promise.
很好
Good...
你知道, 因为你最近, 一直都表现很好
You know, because y-you're doing... you're doing so well.
真的...很好
So... really well.
我不想看到你...
I-I-I'd hate to see you...
干我
Fuck me.
什麽?
What?
我说了
I said,
「快干我」
"fuck me".
布雷克,  你有在听我说吗?
Blake, a-are you listening to me?
你没听到吗
Are you listening to me?
你到底...
What're you... ?
你到底在...
What're you...?
我...想要你
I... want you...
狠狠地干我, 一整晚
to fuck the shit out of me, all night long.
好吧,  停
All right, stop it.
停下
Stop it.
住手
Stop!
我说了快住手
I said stop it!
我欲火焚身
I want it!
求你了?
Please?
求求你
Come on.
快满足我
Give it to me.
我要双份伏特加
Double absolut.
健怡可乐
Diet pepsi.
一杯柑曼怡柯梦
Grand marnier cosmo.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
怎麽
What?
这有可能是最後一次
This may be the last time we're ever standing here
我们几个人一起在这儿痛饮了
at this bar ordering drinks.
就这个吗?  我还以为是什麽大不了的呢
Is that all? I thought it was something serious.
你说波特兰也有巴比伦这样的夜店吗?
Think they have a Babylon in Portland?
那要看波特兰有没有同志了
Huh, you think they have any queers in Portland?
至少有两个我们认识的过去了
Well, there will be at least two that we know of.
你们应该会去看我吧?
Well, you're going to come and visit me, won't you?
如果你想要有人来看你,
If you wanted visitors,
最好还是搬到南部海岸去住
you probably should've moved to south beach.
噢..  小迈
Oh... Mikey.
我们可能再也见不着了
This might be the last time we see each other.
我会想死你的
I'm going to miss you so much.
噢,不,  我不会哭的
No. no, I'm not going to cry.
玛莎史都华说过 (生活风格大师)
As Martha Stewart says,
当生活抛弃了你
when life gets you down,
那就开个派对吧
have a party.
这就是我要做的事
So that's what I'm going to do.
我要为你办个派对
I'm going to give you a party.
好, 得定一个主题
Okay, we'll need a theme.
要一个主题
Need a theme, um...
波特兰那边的人到底有什麽啊?
What the fuck do they have in Portland?
伐木工大叔吗?
Lumberjacks?
或许某天我真会来看看你
Oh, maybe I will come pay you a visit.
老天!  我想到了
Oh my god! I've got it.
法兰绒
Flannel.
我们都得穿法兰绒格子
We'll all wear flannel.
那太好了
Oh, that's perfect.
如果你没有半件的话  还能去借
And if you don't have any, you could always borrow some
向琳赛和茉蕾妮借
from Lindsay and Melanie.
我呢
There, I...
我已经感觉好多了
I feel much better already.
我的妈呀
Oh, my god.
我此後的人生将会如此空虚
My life's going to be so empty.
你还有我啊,  我哪儿都不去
You still have me. I'm not going anywhere.
万岁啊
Hurray.
布莱恩
Brian...
Brian!
等等,  布莱恩
Brian, wait a second.
回家打包去
Go home and pack.
有大卫在弄呢
David's taking care of that.
他...把一切都料理好了
He's... he's taking care of everything.
你到了传说中的波特兰後  有什麽打算
What do you plan on doing when you get to fabulous Portland?
你也准备把什麽都丢给大卫管吗
Are you going to leave all that up to David too?
我根本来不及考虑这些
I haven't had time to think about it.
我们一直忙得无暇顾及
You know, we've just been so busy.
忙着出租他的房屋  处理他的工作
Leasing his house, and... and taking care of his practice
卖掉他的汽车
and shipping his car...
去他妈的「他的」
Fuck "his".
「你们」的呢？
What about "yours"?
真他妈,  管他呢
You know what, fuck it.
你爱怎麽样怎麽样吧
Do whatever you want.
他对你来说太嫩了
He's far too young for you.
想跳舞吗?
Do you want to dance?
老骨头一把了
No, at my advanced years
怕跳舞会摔断尾椎骨啊
I might fall and break my hip.
你别再机机歪歪了好吗?
Nah, would you stop with the old age shit already?
你又不是40岁
It's not like you're 40.
周五晚上有何打算
What're you doing on friday night?
周五啊,周五
Friday, friday, friday...
不知道哇, 我的记忆力
I don't know, my short- term memory's
大不如前了
not what it used to be.
你愿意和我一起去毕业舞会吗?
Do you wanna come to my prom with me?
以什麽身份?  你的监护人吗?
As what? Your chaperone?
我的舞伴
As my date.
呵..我真想去
Huh... I'd love to.
真的吗
Yeah?
但我的晚礼服还在乾洗店那儿没拿回来
But my prom dress is still at the dry cleaners.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
你是疯了还是傻了?
Are you out of your mind?
去找个女孩子吧
Go and ask some girl.
我不想找女孩子
I don't want to go with some girl.
我想约我真正喜欢的人
I want to go with someone I care about.
我就是喜欢个男人,  谁管我?
If that happens to be a guy, who cares?
对阿, 那正是我现在需要的
You know, that's just what I need,
混进一堆小屁孩的舞会里
to be at a dance with a bunch of fucking 18-year-olds.
我以为你喜欢跟小屁孩混一起打炮呢
I thought you liked fucking 18-year-olds.
去买一束胸花
Go buy a corsage...
送给其他人吧
for someone else.
某人看起来「活跃」了一整晚啊
Somebody looks all fucked out.
说得没错
Somebody is.
看来某人需要补充点维他命啊
Somebody needs vitamins.
来杯咖啡
Coffee... over here.
布雷克和我干了一整晚
Blake and I had sex all night.
我只睡了半小时
Got a half- hour's sleep.
这就是所谓「奢侈的烦恼」
Okay, this is what we call a "high-end" problem.
只不过  我不是和他做
Only it wasn't him I was fucking.
是和嗑了药的他
It was some drug.
该死别那麽沾沾自喜
Don't look so goddamn smug.
你是对的  好吗  高兴了吗
You were right, okay? You happy?
不  泰德  我没有幸灾乐祸
No... Teddy, I'm not happy.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我他妈该怎麽办
What the fuck am I going to do?
很简单  亲爱的
Simple, honey.
喝了你的咖啡
You're going to drink your coffee.
给你鲜奶油
Here's the cream.
喝完就回家
Then you're going to go home...
换掉门锁
And you're going to change the locks.
把他拒之门外  就当没他这个人
Just shut him out, like he doesn't exist?
要嘛这样  要麽你就继续自欺欺人
Well, that or you can keep lying to yourself,
继续为他找藉口
you know, making excuses for him,
继续为他每次的消失惶恐不安
Living in a state of panic every time he disappears,
不知他是死还是活
not knowing if he's alive or dead.
然後当他终於一团糟地出现时
And then when he finally shows up a mess,
你继续为再次挽救他喜极而泣
having the supreme joy of putting him back together again.
我  我不能
I-I... I can't.
我  我不能那麽做
I... I can't do that.
-我  我　　　　　　  -好吧
-I just... I just... -Okay.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
那麽  还有第二条路可走
Then, um... Then let's try door number two.
「贝蒂姑姑之家」
"Aunt Betty's B & B".
他可以成为
He can, uh... He can join the
众多耀眼嘉宾中的一员
long list of lustrous guests.
就像「利兹和莱莎」　[女子乐队]
Like Liz and Lisa.
况且
Plus, uh...
这是个很好的考验
It'll be a good test...
看他更爱谁
to see who he loves more,
是你
You...
还是兴奋剂
or crystal.
死屁精！
Fag!
你大爷的  赫伯
Fuck you, Hobbs.
你还好吗
You okay?
该死的混蛋
What an asshole.
谢天谢地
Thank god
这辈子再也不用见到他
I won't have to see him again for the rest of my life.
是啊  或是这里的任何人
Yeah, or... anyone else here either.
我不是说你
I wasn't talking about you.
你去舞会吗
So, are you going to the prom?
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
我就知道
I know.
我本来也没打算去
I wasn't gonna go either,
但黛比说这是一种成人礼
but Deb said it was this rite of passage
如果错过它  我一定会
and if I missed it, then I would
懊悔终生
regret it for the
-所以我邀请了布莱恩  -不会吧
-So I asked Brian.   -No!
但他拒绝了我
He turned me down, though.
真该死
Oh, shit!
你能想像吗
Can you imagine?
-他要去了其他人一定吓疯了 　　　　 -我知道
-People's heads would've exploded. -I know.
一定大快人心  就像在说
It would've been the perfect
「去你妈的  永别了狗屁圣詹姆士学院」
"Fuck you and farewell to St. James Academy".
我很想你  达芙妮
I missed you, Daph.
我也是
You too.
那
So...
我们俩一起去怎麽样
How about you and me going together?
作为舞伴吗
Like a date?
不  像朋友那样
Mmm, like friends...
最好的朋友
Best friends.
只是
Only...
不再尴尬了？
Weirdness over?
绝对不会了
Weirdness definitely over.
好
Okay.
他邀请你去  这真是太可爱了
Oh, I think that's so adorable that he asked you...
尽管你们年龄差距有点大
Despite the somewhat questionable difference in your ages
事实上他在情感上比你还要成熟12岁
and the fact that emotionally he's 12 years your senior.
我不去  太老了
Not going. Too old.
你30岁了  我知道
Oh, so you're 30. I know,
太残酷了  但这是每个人都必须经历的
it's so traumatic, but it is something we all go through.
当然你还得够幸运能活到这把岁数
If you're lucky enough to live that long.
但这有到像世界末日一样吗?
But to carry on like it's the end of your life?
有
It is.
这是全新的开始
It's the beginning.
从全新的角度审视自己
A whole new way of thinking about yourself.
体会一种全新的归属感
Feeling a whole new sense of entitlement,
和成就感
and accomplishment.
这还真像欧蕾抗皱产品的广告词
That's from the "La Jeunesse" anti-aging commercial.
那广告词是我写的
I wrote that fucking copy.
好吧  算我引用了大师的名言
Okay. well, I guess I only quote from the masters. hmm.
但事实也确实如此
But it's the truth.
我期待皱纹  白头发
I want wrinkles, I want to have grey hair.
期待盖斯让我抱孙子
I want Gus to make me a grandmother.
我还想和茉蕾妮一起慢慢变老
I want to grow old with Melanie.
你想让我在这里吐出来吗
Do you want me to puke right here?
我不要白头发和皱纹
I don't want grey hair and wrinkles.
也不想当爷爷
I don't want to be a grandfather.
当然更不想
And I definitely...
和茉蕾妮一起变老
don't want to grow old with Melanie...
-或者其他任何人   -那你想要什麽
-Or anyone else.  -What do you want?
这个
This.
很好看
It's very beautiful.
也许你是对的
You know, maybe you're right.
也许我是该庆祝30岁的到来
Maybe I should celebrate turning 30.
给自己买个特别的礼物
Give myself something very special.
这就对了
Now you're talking.
大卫  大卫
David? David?
-怎麽了  　　　-我的法兰绒格纹衬衫呢
-What is it?   -Where's my plaid flannel?
我一直放在这里
It used to be right here.
我打包了
Oh, oh, I packed it.
那我去艾美特的聚会穿什麽
What am I supposed to wear to Emmett's party?
大家都要穿法兰绒格纹的
You're supposed to wear flannel.
这里
Here.
-试试这件  　　-谢了
-Try that on.  -Thanks.
一定很适合你
You'll look good in that.
我穿太紧  就给你好了
That's too small on me. You keep it.
我不要你的旧衣服
I don't need your hand-me-downs.
我只要  有人听我说话
What I need is... Somebody who listens to me.
怎麽了
What?
我是说
Well, to think about...
到波特兰後我要做什麽
w-what I'm going to do when we get to Portland.
我们甚至还没讨论过
I mean, we haven't even discussed it.
好吧  那现在讨论
Okay, let's discuss it.
好  我觉得
W-well, I... I thought that, um...
我应该不会再到超市工作了
You know, maybe I wouldn't work at another Big Q,
所以我可能会
you know, that maybe I'd, uh...
做些完全不同的尝试
Um... I-I'd try something totally different.
全新的方向
You know, a whole new track,
甚至回到大学
maybe even go back to college.
嗯
Um...
我差点忘了
Uh... oh, I just remembered,
我告诉过要租房的人
I told the people that are leasing the house
我们走前会把纱门装上
I'd put the screen doors in before we left.
让我来吧
Oh, I can do it.
没事  我来就好
Oh, that's okay. I'll take care of it.
以前每年都是我
Well, I used to help my mom put
替我妈装纱门的
on the screen doors every year.
交给我  我手上功夫很棒  还记得吗
It's okay, I'm good with my hands, remember?
-嗨  亲爱的  -快进来  快进来
-Hi, honey.  -Come in, come in, come in.
好
Okay!
嗨  宝贝
Hi, baby. aww...
见鬼了　好像在森林里
I feel like I'm in a fuckin' forest.
连闻起来都他妈的像
It even smells like a fuckin' forest.
这是松树味喷雾
That would be the miracle
带来的奇蹟
of pine-scented spray.
哦  老天
Oh, god!
妈　大家特地把这里布置成西北的风格
It's supposed to be the great northwest, ma.
好让大卫和我及早体验新家的感觉
To make David and me feel at home.
就差一头熊在树丛里拉一坨屎了
All we need now is a bear to shit in the woods.
我可以邀请「人孔盖」的 (双关)
I could ask Big Hairy Al
大支毛男艾尔过来
who works at the manhole to come over.
他最爱玩粪便了
He's into scat.
哦  老天
Eww, jesus.
快捂住耳朵  小宝贝
Cover your ears, sweetheart,
艾美特阿姨真恶心
Your aunty Em is being gross.
怎麽了
What?
你说要穿法兰绒格纹
You said wear flannel.
请允许我说  你们两从来没有看起来这麽
May I say, you two have never looked more...
男人婆过
butch.
你不也是
Well, neither have you.
法兰绒格纹
Flannel.
不就是拉子的内衣吗
Isn't that lesbian lingerie?
插根阴茎更好  怎麽样
Stick a dick in it, would you?
太好笑了
I think that's funny.
布莱恩在哪
Where's Brian?
他总是姗姗来迟
He's always fashionably late.
你和他谈过没
Have you talked to him yet?
这松饼有放白脱牛奶吗？
Are these buttermilk?
没
No.
作为今晚的女主人
Well, may I suggest,
我有个提议
as your hostess for the evening
快去和他谈谈
That you do so?
这是惜别会  不是调解会
It's a goodbye party, not an intervention.
但是越早说再见越好
Then the sooner you say goodbye, the better.
不用现在就和我告别
You don't have to say goodbye to me right now.
我明天才走
I'm not leaving till tomorrow.
我们不是在说你  宝贝
We weren't talking about you, sweetie.
你都收拾好了吗
So, you all packed?
是啊  现在我所有的东西都装上了货车
Yeah, my entire life is on a moving van
向波特兰开去了
headed to Ｐortland.
你不是想退缩了吧？
You aren't getting cold feet, are you?
自从我住这儿以後
I haven't had cold feet
脚从来没冷过　("脚冷" 也意指退缩)
since I lived here.
还记得非得猛敲暖气管
Remember banging on the pipes
房东才会打开暖气吗
so the landlord would turn on some heat?
总好过去敲房东 (bang也指上了房东)
It's better than banging the landlord.
这
Well...
亲爱的
Well, honey...
如果你什麽时候想回来了  只要
You ever want to come home, you just, um...
只要敲鞋跟三下就可以了
you just click your heels three times.
我觉得我最想念的人一定会是你  稻草人
I guess I'll miss you most of all, Scarecrow.
可怜的家伙
Poor guys.
他们没事吧
Are they gonna be all right?
嗯  他们会没事的
Yeah, they'll be fine.
你呢
What about you?
天啊  迈克  你只是去波特兰
For chrissakes, Michael, you're only going to Portland,
又不是要上月球
not to the moon.
况且还有电话和飞机
They got planes and phones
可以随时往返呢
that go both ways, honey.
你和维克叔叔随时可以过来玩
And you and uncle vic can come and visit any time you want.
说话要算数哦
We may take you up on that.
但就像我说的那样  这没什麽大不了的
But like I said, it's no big deal.
我一直都是这麽说的  对吧维克
Isn't that what I've been saying, Vic?
她确实一直都这麽说
She's been saying that.
来  抱我一下  没什麽大不了的
So give me a hug, and that'll be that.
妈
Ma?
你不打算放开我了吗
Are you going to let me go?
我很想放开你  但没办法
I'd like to sweetheart, but I can't.
什麽叫没办法
What do you mean, you can't?
我的手臂动弹不了了
My arms won't move.
妈  你快要把我闷死了
Ma, you're suffocating me.
我不是在说笑
I'm not fuckin' kidding.
大卫  维克叔叔
David, uncle Vic?
好了  放开吧
Oh, okay, okay.
我们一起来把她拉开  数到三
Come on, let's give her a pull. On three...
-过来  　　　-我可没有乱动你房间里的东西
- Come here. -I didn't touch anything in your room.
我不是要说这个
That's not what I was going to say.
听着  我要你帮我个忙
Look, I need you to do me a favour.
什麽  要我就此消失吗
What, disappear?
我早就不抱这种愿望了
I gave up all hope of that happening a long time ago.
我希望我不在的日子你可以帮我照顾我妈
I need you to take care of my mom while I'm away.
不要让她工作太劳累  还有
You know, make sure she doesn't work too hard, and...
帮她做做家务
and help her around the house,
倒倒垃圾什麽的
and... and take out the trash
如果你看见她感到寂寞
And if you see that she is lonely,
就过去陪她坐一会儿
just sit with her a while
让她把心里想说的话说出来
and let her talk.
这些话可能你已经听过很多遍了
Even if you've heard it before.
但有时候她只是需要一个忠实的听众
Because sometimes she just needs to know that someone is listening
我一定做到
I promise.
我爱你的朋友们
I love your friends.
他们就像家人一样
They are like family.
不是「像」  他们就是
Not "like"; they are.
因为我们信任彼此
It's because we trust each other.
你不信任我吗
You don't trust me?
有什麽让我无法信任的吗
Do I have reason not to?
好吧  听着  我们还是
All right, look, let's not pretend there isn't a moose
不要再粉饰太平了
in the middle of the room, okay?
我知道你又嗑药了
I know you're using again.
在我买给你的那件西装口袋里
I found one of your little "favours"
我发现了你的一瓶「小玩意儿」
in the pocket of the suit I bought you.
我们说好要相互信任的
Huh, talk about trust.
我没要找什麽  是它自己掉出来的
I wasn't looking for it. okay, it just fell out.
你信也好不信也好  我都不在乎
You can believe me or not, I really don't care.
我一直想假装没看到
Since then, I've been trying to pretend I didn't see it.
只是  我做不到
Only, I can't.
我不能看着你就这样把自己毁了
Not when I see you destroying your life.
我恐怕是一再沉沦  一再让你失望了
I was afraid of disappointing you, of failing again.
的确
Well, you have.
我不能和一个毒虫过活
And I can't live with an addict.
我也不能和一个毒虫做爱
And I can't make love to an addict.
我一想到
And it sickens me
你对你自己所做的一切就作呕
to think about what you're doing to a person
我这麽关心你  在乎你
I happen to care a whole lot about
你却这样糟蹋自己
who obviously cares so little about himself.
所以我别无选择
So I have no choice...
只能跟你分手了
Except to say goodbye.
我也不想这样的
I don't wanna be like this!
那就去戒毒所
Then check yourself into rehab.
要鹿肉乾吗
Hm. uh, Moose Jerky?
离别  比我想得要艰难多了
It's harder than I thought... saying goodbye.
我们凌晨就走还真是一件好事
It's a good thing we're leaving first thing in the morning.
实际上  我把机票改到明天晚上了
Actually, I changed the reservation for tomorrow night.
什麽
What?
我说我把机票改到明天晚上了
I said I changed the reservation till tomorr...
你为什麽没有告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
这很重要吗
Well, does it matter?
不重要才怪
Obviously not.
迈克  这只是一点小变动
Well, Michael, it's just a little change of plan.
我还有一些事情没有交代清楚
I've just got a few things I gotta clear up...
我可以帮你完成啊
Which I could've helped you with,
可是  我每次提出要帮你  你都拒绝
Except... every time I offer, you refuse.
你每次都要亲自动手
You have to do everything yourself.
我只是觉得
I just thought...
不 你只是觉得我没有处理事情的能力
No, you just thought I couldn't handle it.
我他妈的连装个纱门都不会
That I can't hang a fucking screen door.
你这是怎麽了
What the fuck is wrong with you?
你觉得我只会跟在你的身後
You just think I'm going to go along,
照你说的做
do whatever you want,
甚至连时间和方式也要受你限制
on your terms and your time.
就像个孩子或  模范老婆
Like a child, or a... or a trophy wife.
什麽事情都由你做主  而我只能在旁边附和
You just make all the decisions, and I'll say "yes, dear".
只有我要放弃我生命中的所有
Only I'm the one giving up everything in my goddamn life.
包括我的家人  我的朋友
My family, my friends,
我的工作去跟你在一起
my job to be with you.
我不得不这麽怀疑
And I have to wonder,
如果换作是你
that if the situation was reversed,
你也会为我做同样的事情吗
would you have done the same for me?
我想我已经知道答案了
Well, I guess that's an answer
妈的
Fuck you!
混蛋
Asshole!
你他妈的在干什麽
What the fuck were you doing?
你他妈的又在干什麽呢
What the fuck are you doing?
我来看看你为什麽没有参加我的告别派对
I came here to see why you didn't come to my farewell party.
什麽派对
What party?
别他妈给我装蒜了
You know goddamn well.
除了你大家都去了
Everybody was there but you.
想起来了  大卫和迈克的法兰绒格纹衬衫告别会
Oh, right, David and Michael's "farewell in flannel".
我忙着为自己进行庆祝呢
Well, I've been having a little celebration of my own
纪念我华丽的三十岁
in honour of my big three-O.
就用这玩意儿吗
With this?
正是  送给自己一个特别的礼物
Yeah, to give myself a very special gift.
什麽特别？
Like what?
就是给我自已这辈子最棒的高潮
Like the greatest fucking orgasm of my life.
我看是你这辈子最後的高潮吧
Try the last fucking orgasm of your life.
你可能会弄死自己的
You could kill yourself.
这绝不是最糟糕的事
Well, that wouldn't be the worst thing that could happen.
带着一身荣光离去
To go out in a blaze of glory,
就像柯特·科本（摇滚歌手  27岁自杀）
Like Cobain...
詹姆斯·迪恩（影星  24岁死於车祸）
James Dean...
吉米·亨德里克斯（吉他大师  28死亡）
Hendrix.
他们都是传奇
They're all legends.
他们将永远年轻
They'll always be young.
永远风华正茂
And they'll always be beautiful.
他们也永远是死人了
And they'll always be dead.
「如果害怕冒险  生命还有什麽意义呢」
"life not worth living if you not take risk."
你不能这麽做
You're not going through with it.
如果我想体验窒息式性爱的快感
If I want to experience the joys of scarfing,
那又他妈的关你什麽事
what the hell business is it of yours?
这当然关我的事了
It's my business
因为当该死的清洁女工
'cause I'm the one who'll get the call
发现你勃起的屍体挂在梁上
that the god- damn cleaning lady's found you
警察打电话找的人肯定是我
hanging from the rafters with a fucking boner.
妈的  迈克
Ah... fuck you, Michael.
去你的
Fuck you.
你为什麽非要破坏一切呢
Why do you always have to ruin everything?
破坏  我这是在救你的命
Ruin? I'm saving you! ah?
就像托比·哈珀救了星际队长一样
Just like Toby Harper saved captain Astro
在《星际队长》第231期
in issue 231 of Astro comics.
当时星际队长认为自己
When captain astro thought that
失去了所有的超能力
he'd lost all of his super power
天啊  你太可悲了
God, you are so pathetic.
不  可悲的是你
No, you are!
你难道不知道你还是魅力十足吗？
Don't you know that you still have your powers?
你全部的魅力
All your powers.
你永远都不会失去的
And you always will.
不管你是18岁还是30岁
Whether you're 18 or you're 30,
50岁  甚至100岁
or you're 50, or you're 100.
你将永远保持年轻
You will always be young
也将永远风华绝代
And you will always be beautiful.
你可是他妈的「布莱恩·肯尼」啊
You're Brian Kinney, for fuck's sake!
这儿的工作人员好像很不错
Well, the staff seems very nice.
都很热心
They're really helpful.
确实
They do.
他们说他们可以随时满足你的要求
They said you can get anything you want, anytime.
-全天都有零食供应的  　　　　　　　　　-不错啊
- You know, they got snacks all day... - That's good.
如果你有什麽需要的话  只要
Yeah. And if you need anything, you just, um...
我会的
I... I will.
我想你知道
Look, I-I... I want you to know
我有多开心
how happy...
说「开心」不太恰当
Well... happy's not the right word.
不是开心  是感激
Not happy, but uh... grateful
和宽慰
and relieved
你能这麽做
I am that you're doing this.
这都是为了我们  对吧
Well, it's for us, right?
对
Right.
那麽
So...
-我们晚上见  　　　　　　-晚上见
- I'll see you tonight?  - Tonight.
对了  还有一件事
Oh, one more thing before I forget...
我想你可能会想听这个
Huh, thought you might like to listen to that.
「茶花女」
"La traviata".
-你最爱的歌剧  　　　　　-是啊  这个是
- Your favourite opera.  - Yeah, it's...
我唯一知道的歌剧
the only opera that... I know.
只是
Except...
你不是说结尾的时候他们又在一起了
you said at the end they get back together
而且唱了很多华美的合唱
and sing many glorious duets.
这个应该在续集里吧
Guess that's the sequel.
茶花女2
"Traviata 2".
考虑到你的感受
Considering how you feel,
我觉得你不要去比较好
I think it's probably a good idea that you not go.
你觉得比较好
You think it's a good idea.
老天  迈克  你还想让我说什麽
For Chris' sakes, Michael, what do you want me to say?
说「我们都觉得」  如果你偶尔这样说
"We think." You know, if you used the word occasionally
你可能已经习惯了
you might actually get used to it.
很明显是你自己觉得这主意不太好的
You're the one who's obviously decided it's not a good idea.
只是这次不是纱门
Only this time it's not about screen doors
也不是改航班  这次是布莱恩
or changing flights. This time it's about Brian.
如果你当初知道他不走的话
If you knew he wasn't leaving,
你绝对不会答应和我一起去的
you would've never agreed to go.
不是的  大卫
No, David.
你应该很高兴知道  这次和他无关
You'll be happy to know, this time it's not about him.
是你
It's about you.
车马上就要来了
The car'll be here any minute.
我可以送你去机场的
I can take you to the airport.
我知道  不过最好不要
I know you can, but I'd rather you didn't.
很好  你说了算
Okay, fine. Have it your way.
我说了算
The way I always do?
不是那样的
That's not what I was going to say.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我告诉过你多少次了
How many times have I told you,
你不需要一直道歉的  迈克
You don't have to keep apologizing, Michael?
我知道  可是
I know I don't, but...
另外
Aside from that...
应该是我要道歉的
I'm the one that should be apologizing to you.
很抱歉我没有考虑到你的感受
I'm sorry I disregarded your feelings,
很抱歉我自作主张
that I didn't include you in the decisions,
想让你和我一起走  还有  不
that I expected you to come, and, no...
我不确定我能做到你所做的
I'm not sure that I could do the same.
很感谢你的道歉  不过
Well, I appreciate that, but that's...
我要说的不是这个
That's not what I was going to say.
我的人生怎麽过
It's not up to you
不该是你来决定
to decide what I should do with my life.
是我自己该决定
That's up to me.
如果我不自己决定  那就是我的错
And if I didn't do it, then it's my fault.
而且
And...
也许下一次我应该
maybe next time I should just...
先想清楚
I should think things through
再答应
more clearly befond I say yes.
我希望你能改变主意
Well, I hope you'll decide to change your mind.
如果你想来的话
And if you do...
我会等你
I'll be waiting.
这一次
And this time,
轮到你来决定了
On your time... and your terms.
各位  请注意
Attention, everyone.
还记得刚刚上楼那个
Remember that cute little twink
穿着短版T恤和迷彩裤的
in the midriff-t and fatigues
可爱小鬼吗
who went up the stairs?
那麽  请看看现在是谁走下来了
Well, just take a look at who is coming down.
我靠  阳光男孩
Holy shit, sunshine!
谁能想到呢
Well, what do ya know?
小嫩鸡现在变成
The little chicken's become
雄赳赳气昂昂的大公鸡了 (cock暗指阴茎)
cock-of-the-walk.
亲爱的  你看上去  很美
Sweetheart, you look... beautiful.
老天  连我都想追你了
Jesus, I could go for you myself.
那你得先过了我这关
If I don't beat you to him.
真不敢相信你把签名本都带来了
I can't believe you brought your autograph book with you.
你不会料到在戒毒所可能遇见谁
Well, you never know who you might see in rehab.
你好  我们是来看望布雷克·维泽奇的
Hi, uh, we're here to visit with Blake Wyzecki.
抱歉  布雷克自己办出院了
Sorry, Blake checked himself out.
他  他今天下午才住进来的啊
He just... he just checked himself in this afternoon.
他走了
He's gone.
这算什麽  你们
W-what... what, you just let
能让病人随便出院的吗
people leave when ever they want?
这里是自愿的  我们不能逼别人留下来
It's a voluntary commitment, we can't force people to stay.
他有说他要去哪吗
Did he say where he was going?
他  他有留言吗
Did he... did he leave a message?
你是泰德吗
Are you Ted?
是的
That's right.
这是他留给你的
He left this for you.
你不是说你死都不会来一个
I thought you said you wouldn't be caught dead
挤满了小鬼头的地方吗
in a room full of 18-year-olds.
我想我应该重新体验一下年轻的感觉
I thought I'd recapture my lost youth.
你看起来很辣  达芙妮
You look hot, Daphne.
我都想上你了
I'd fuck you.
你  你也是  布莱恩
Uh, you... you too, Brian.
不介意把舞伴借给我一会吧
Mind if I borrow your date?
「你可以舞一曲」
You can dance
「和那个凝视你的男人跳舞」
Every dance with the guy who gives you the eye
「让他紧紧拥抱着你」
Let him hold you tight
「你可以微笑」
You can smile every smile
「对那个在苍白月色下下」
for the man who held your hand
「紧握你手的男人微笑」
neath the pale moonlight
「但是别忘记是谁带你回家」
but don't forget who's taking you home
「你又该属於谁的怀抱」
and in whose arms you're gonna be
「亲爱的  把最後一支舞留给我」
so darling save the last dance for me
「我知道」
Oh I know
「这音乐像是闪烁的红酒那样动人」
that the music's fine like sparkling wine
「去尽享花样年华吧」
go and have your fun
「欢笑  歌唱」
laugh and sing
「但当我不在你身边」
but while we're apart
「不要把你的心交给别人」
don't give your heart to anyone
「别忘记是谁带你回家」
but don't forget who's taking you home
「你又该属於谁的怀抱」
and in whose arms you're gonna be
「亲爱的  把最後一支舞留给我」
so darling save the last dance for me
「宝贝  难道你不知道我如此爱你」
baby don't you know I love you so
「我们相拥时难道你感觉不到」
can't you feel it when we touch
「我永远不会让你离去」
I will never, never let you go
「我是如此爱你」
I love you oh so much
「你可以跳舞」
you can dance
「漫漫长夜尽情舞蹈  可黎明之时」
go and carry on till the night is gone
「你该回到我的身边」
and it's time to go
「如果他问你」
if he asks
「是否独自一人  是否可以带你回家」
if you're all alone can he take you home
「你一定要说不」
you must tell him no
「别忘记是谁带你回家」
cause don't forget who's taking you home
「你又该属於谁的怀抱」
and in whose arms you're gonna be
「亲爱的  把最後一支舞留给我」
so darling save the last dance for me
「别忘记是谁带你回家」
cause don't forget who's taking you home
「你又该属於谁的怀抱」
and in whose arms you're gonna be
「亲爱的  把最後一支舞留给我」
so darling save the last dance for me
「把最後一支舞留给我」
save the last dance for me
「把最後一支」
save the last...
美国航空476号航班现在开始登机
American airlines flight 476 now boarding at gate...
小姐  小姐
Stewardess? Stewardess,
990航班起飞了吗
Has flight 990 left yet?
他们已经开始登机了  在39号登机口
I believe they've already started boarding. Gate 39.
想赶上飞机的话  你得快点了
If you want to make it, you'd better hurry.
「别忘记是谁带你回家 」
Don't forget who's taking you home
「你又该属於谁的怀抱」
And in whose arms you're gonna be
你看到他们的表情了吗
Did you see their faces?
我们给了他们一场终身难忘的毕业舞会
Yeah, we gave 'em a prom they'll never forget.
我也不会忘的
Me neither.
这是我一生中最棒的一晚了
It's the best night of my life.
就算它无可救药地浪漫
Yeah, even if it was ridiculously romantic.
回头见
Later.
贾斯汀
Justin!
老天  我靠
God... dammit!
不要  不要
No-no-no-no- no-no-no-no-no.
老天
God!
4408114a06754f1194cd22477df7a928